writecheck.com 2016-10-31

# Privacy Pledge — Plagiarism Checker | WriteCheck by Turnitin

Effective Date: February 20, 2015

 _We understand that privacy is a sensitive issue and we take the protection of your information seriously. This Privacy Pledge explains our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your personal information is collected and used. This Pledge applies to all personal information collected or submitted on the WriteCheck.com,  Turnitin.com and TurnitinUK.com web site (the "Site")._

WriteCheck is an online service provided by Turnitin, LLC to secondary and higher education schools. For us to provide the level of service our customers and prospective customers expect, it is necessary for us to collect and store specific, private information from Site visitors and users of our service.

Turnitin has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers the websites [www.turnitin.com](http://www.turnitin.com/) and [turnitinuk.com](http://www.turnitinuk.com/en_gb/). The TRUSTe program does not cover behind the login of these sites and the information that may be collected through our mobile application. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

To make this Privacy Pledge easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where we request your personal information. Although this Site provides links to third-party web sites, these third parties are not covered by the Turnitin Privacy Pledge. Turnitin doesn’t assume any responsibility for the privacy or security of information you provide to any third party, whether through linked web sites or by any other means.

By using this Site, you agree that you have reviewed and understand our Usage Policy and this Privacy Pledge to your full satisfaction, that you accept and agree to our Usage Policy and this Privacy Pledge, and that Turnitin is permitted to use your personal information according to the clauses below.

## 1\. Personal Information

The following personal information is collected: Name, email, phone, job title, school name, address, etc.

REGISTRATION

When you register to use our service, we request your personal information for these purposes:

  1. To verify your identity and determine your status to register in connection with your specific academic institution.
  2. To obtain your contact information so we can correctly administer your account.
  3. To inform you of changes in the functionality, auxiliary services, and promotions of the Turnitin service.

TRIAL

When you request a trial of our service, we request your personal information for these purposes:

  1. To inform you of changes in Turnitin's functionality, Turnitin's auxiliary services, and Turnitin's promotions.
  2. To request your evaluation and recommendations for the Turnitin service.

PAPER SUBMISSION

When anyone requests access to our paper submission web pages, we request personal information for these purposes:

  1. To identify the individual connected to any uploaded text.
  2. To provide receipt and confirmation of successful text uploads.

The type of information we request is connected to a specific purpose. For example, we collect personal contact information such as name, physical address, telephone number, and email address for a registered user in order to facilitate use of the Turnitin service and facilitate customer relations. In addition to the specific uses noted above, Turnitin also uses your personally identifiable information to process your requests and transactions.

Turnitin may also use your personally identifiable information to prevent harm or injury, to prevent fraud, to protect our legal interests, to comply with or respond to legal process, and to comply with applicable laws.

Access to personal information by third parties will only occur via signed or electronic consent by registered users as stated in our registration agreement. This approval includes, but is not limited to, one registered user allowing Turnitin to provide his or her contact information to another registered user for document source analysis tracking. For example, if material uploaded to our database matches material from a later upload, contact information related to the former is given to the registered user associated with the latter upload for follow-up if the former specifically consents. As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets, or Turnitin might be acquired by another company. In any of these circumstances, personal information in our databases may be included among the transferred assets. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. You may opt out of marketing communications [here.](http://go.turnitin.com/preferences)

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you and to improve site functionality.

## 2\. Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Turnitin, LLC . These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We use cookies to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference) and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site.

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store select preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site use LSOs such as HTML 5 and Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please [click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

We do not serve ads on our site. We partner with a third party to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads on other sites, you may opt-out by [clicking here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union [click here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)) Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

## 3\. Choice

When you provide personally identifiable information to us, you will be able to choose whether we may disclose such information in a personally identifiable form to a third party or whether the information may be used in personally identifiable form for purposes different from the purposes for which it was originally collected or that you have subsequently authorized.

You will have the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us when we first request your personal information. You can also opt out of receiving further communications by visiting our[email preferences page](http://go.turnitin.com/preferences). You can request removal of your personally identifiable information from our databases by contacting us as noted in Section 14 (Notices) below. To honor your request, we will need the exact information you want removed, and information sufficient for us to identify the type of communication you received from us.

## 4\. Transfer to Unrelated Third Parties

Except in connection with the purposes for which it was originally collected, no personal information will be provided to a third party. If we transfer personal information to a third party that is acting as our agent, we will require that the third party agree to confidentiality requirements. We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy pledge. We do not sell personal information to third parties.

## 5\. Access or Change Your Personal Information

You can access, correct, amend, or delete the personal information that you have provided us at any time via this Site by following these steps:

  1. Log in to your account using your user name and password.
  2. Click the "user info" link on the navigation bar to open your user profile and view, correct, amend or delete personal information.
  3. Or by [emailing our Customer Support](mailto:tiisupport@turnitin.com?subject=Personal%20Information%20Request) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.

If you request access to your personal information from Turnitin, we will respond to your request within 30 days.

## 6\. Security

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. We have physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards in place to protect your personal information, including the use of passwords to gain access to your personal information. To protect your privacy and security, you must keep your password confidential. However, even with such measures, no one is able to guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not be able to bypass these measures or otherwise capture information you provide over the Internet.

## 7\. Data Integrity

We take reasonable steps to make sure that the personal information in our systems is relevant for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current. We retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. You may stop using the services at any time. You do not need to specifically inform Turnitin when you stop using the Services. You may delete your account at any time by logging in to your account or by [sending us an email](mailto:tiisupport@turnitin.com?subject=Delete%20Account%20Request).

## 8\. Enforcement

Turnitin will conduct periodic reviews of compliance to verify that this Privacy Pledge is accurate, comprehensive, prominently displayed, complete, implemented, and accessible. Any employee who violates this Privacy Pledge may be subject to disciplinary action.

## 9\. Special Rules Applicable to Data Collected or Processed in the European Union and Switzerland

This Privacy Pledge applies to all personally identifiable data that is subject to the European Union's Data Protection Directive 95/46 EC and that is transferred to the United States, even if not collected at this Site. Turnitin has enrolled in the Safe Harbor System established by the U.S. Department of Commerce to meet the requirements of the European Commission's Directive on Data Protection for the EU and Switzerland.

Turnitin complies with the U.S.–E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S.–Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Turnitin has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Turnitin’s certification, please visit [http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/.](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/)

Onward transfers will be permitted only to other persons or entities who have agreed to provide a continuing adequate level of protection through participation in the Safe Harbor program or one of the other means permitted under EU Directive 95/46 EC and implementing Member State laws.

If you have any concern or complaint regarding Turnitin's compliance with the Safe Harbor Principles, please contact Turnitin as noted in Section 14 (Notices) below. Turnitin will investigate your concern or complaint and will attempt to resolve the matter with you. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe [here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

## 10\. Changes to this Policy

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Pledge at any time. Please check the Privacy Pledge when you use the Site to ensure that you are aware of any changes in our privacy practices. Our Privacy Pledge will indicate the date it was last updated. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you via e-mail at the last email address you have provided to us. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. If you elect not to allow us to use your information in this different manner, we will continue to use such information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

## 11\. Social Media (Features) and Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, record which pages you are visiting on our site, and set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy pledge of the company providing the specific Feature.

## 12\. Blog

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, [email us](mailto:tiisupport@turnitin.com?subject=Personal%20Information%20Request). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. You may also post a comment on our blog with the use of a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policies.

## 13\. Testimonials

With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name, title and school name. If you want your testimonial updated or removed please [contact us](mailto:tiisupport@turnitin.com?subject=Testimonial%20Request).

## 14\. Third Party Websites

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from ours. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Web site you visit.

## 15\. Notices

Please direct all inquiries regarding the Privacy Pledge as follows:

  1. Contact us by email at [legal@turnitin.com](mailto:legal@turnitin.com).
  2. Specify the exact nature of your inquiry.
  3. Provide us with your contact information for follow-up response.

## Corporate Address

Turnitin, LLC  
1111 Broadway, 3rd floor  
Oakland, California 94607  
Phone: +1 510-764-7600   
Fax: +1 510-764-7612
